<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: english | /lerrua]]></title>
  <link href="http://lerrua.com/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lerrua.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-17T20:24:54-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://lerrua.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Igor P. Leroy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started with Data Science]]></title>
    <link href="http://lerrua.com/blog/2016/03/17/getting-started-with-data-science/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-17T20:23:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://lerrua.com/blog/2016/03/17/getting-started-with-data-science</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!--more-->


<p>Data Science has gained a lot of market strength in recent years, a hitherto academic market now draws attention of large companies and startups.
Who here does not know someone on Linkedin that was a software engineer or Developer and after now became a Data Analyst or Data Scientist?
It is a new wave of professionals with experience in programming languages like Python, R, Scala, Java along with experience or academic training in areas of mathematics, such as statistics.</p>

<p>Attending talks in the Python community events and motivated by good friends who already work in the area, I decided to invest in this field and in October last year started some courses on my own.</p>

<p>The first course I did was the <em>Introduction to Big Data</em> at Coursera, offered by the University of California, San Diego. My experience was extremely positive, which motivated me to create a kind of script for me to follow in the coming months.</p>

<p>This article shows my studies grid, which can be a guide for people interested to invest in this new world of information. But if you are one of those people who have never heard about Data Science or Machine Learning, I strongly recommend reading these articles <a href="https://medium.com/@ageitgey/machine-learning-is-fun-80ea3ec3c471#.zcy0625w8">Machine Learning is fun</a> and <a href="http://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2016/01/complete-tutorial-learn-data-science-python-scratch-2">Learn Data Science with Python from Scratch</a>.</p>

<p>Moving forward, all materials listed here are in English, subtitled and not so scary for anyone who is not fluent, with a little effort you can proceed. Worth highlighting that most of the courses showed here are <strong>free</strong>!</p>

<h3>Introductory courses</h3>

<p>For beginners Udacity has a large collection of free stuff and excellent quality. These courses have a 3 week period of average, I recommend doing some parallel. Some of them are very short that can be made in a single weekend.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Intro to Data Analysis &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud170">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud170</a></p></li>
<li><p>Intro to Data Science &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud359">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud359</a></p></li>
<li><p>Intro to Statistics &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/st101">https://www.udacity.com/courses/st101</a></p></li>
<li><p>Intro to Machine Learning &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud120">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud120</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>In addition to the first list we have the <a href="https://khanacademy.org/math">math session</a> with Khan Academy lessons of algebra, probability and statistics and Udemy with <a href="https://www.udemy.com/big-data-basics-hadoop-mapreduce-hive-pig-spark/">Big Data Basics: Hadoop, MapReduce, Hive, Pig &amp; Spark</a>.</p>

<p>It sounds like a lot for a material for beginners, right? Correct, but this is an overview of the Data Science covers, if you like the statistical topics then you have a greater focus on Machine Learning but the preference for visualization and data analysis then perhaps the topics of Big Data will be more interesting.</p>

<h3>Intermediate level</h3>

<p>The intermediate and advanced level courses are in the script, but necessarily in that order. In this case the choice is more on demand, depending on the need of a project or in a specific study.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Intro to Hadoop and MapReduce &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud617">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud617</a></p></li>
<li><p>Real-Time Analytics with Apache Storm &ndash;  <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud381">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud381</a></p></li>
<li><p>Data Visualization and D3.js &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud507">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud507</a></p></li>
<li><p>A/B Testing &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud257">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud257</a></p></li>
<li><p>Intro to Descriptive Statistics &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud827">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud827</a></p></li>
<li><p>Intro to Inferential Statistics &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud201">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud201</a></p></li>
<li><p>Linear Algebra Refresher Course &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud953">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud953</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Advanced level</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Model Building and Validation &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud919">https://www.udacity.com/courses/ud919</a></p></li>
<li><p>Deepin Learning &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/deep-learning--ud730">https://www.udacity.com/course/deep-learning--ud730</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>This was the list of free courses that interested me, as you can see the Udacity provides a good structure for those who have time to invest. With good discipline and good personal management in a few months we can evolve a lot without spending one penny.</p>

<p>But I would also like to add some paid courses to this script, I woud include <a href="https://www.udemy.com/user/frankkane/">Frank Kane</a> on that list. His courses are relatively cheap with a number of weeks and very practical material with real examples, they are:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Taming Big Data with Apache Spark &ndash; Hands On! &ndash; <a href="https://www.udemy.com/taming-big-data-with-apache-spark-hands-on/">https://www.udemy.com/taming-big-data-with-apache-spark-hands-on/</a></p></li>
<li><p>Taming Big Data with MapReduce and Hadoop &ndash; Hands On! &ndash; <a href="https://www.udemy.com/taming-big-data-with-mapreduce-and-hadoop/">https://www.udemy.com/taming-big-data-with-mapreduce-and-hadoop/</a></p></li>
<li><p>Data Science and Machine Learning with Python &ndash; Hands On! <a href="https://www.udemy.com/data-science-and-machine-learning-with-python-hands-on/">https://www.udemy.com/data-science-and-machine-learning-with-python-hands-on/</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Each of these courses cost on average $25, then the cost-benefit is huge in comparison to specializations at Coursera or nanodegree at Udacity, I will explain what they are below.</p>

<h3>Specializations</h3>

<p>The Coursera specializations are longer courses that usually last 4 to 6 months and need a greater commitment than the free courses that I quoted above. These specializations are a pack of grouped courses, you can purchase individually and the last course is a final project called Capstone Project that needs to be done so you can get your certification.</p>

<p>Generally the full specialization has at least 5 courses, some even 10. Each course has an average value of $60.</p>

<p>The Introduction to Big Data that started in October is the first course of Big Data Specialization I will complete this year.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Big Data Specialization, UC San Diego &ndash; <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/big-data">https://www.coursera.org/specializations/big-data</a></p></li>
<li><p>Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington &ndash; <a href="https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning">https://www.coursera.org/specializations/machine-learning</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>These two specializations are some of my goals for 2016, noting that the Coursera offers other <a href="https://www.coursera.org/browse/data-science">specializations of Data Science</a>, the list is huge.</p>

<p>The nanodegrees of Udacity are not in my plans for now, not for quality but for reasons of time and cost. Nanodegrees are huge courses ranging from 9 to 12 months and has a monthly cost of $200, something a little out of my Brazilian reality with the high dollar today. But is recommended for those who want to run into this mini-college, they promise guaranteed job and a teacher available to you. The course&rsquo;s grade are very good, in partnership with companies like Google and Facebook:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Data Analyst Nanodegree &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/nanodegrees-new-s/nd002">https://www.udacity.com/nanodegrees-new-s/nd002</a></p></li>
<li><p>Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree &ndash; <a href="https://www.udacity.com/course/machine-learning-engineer-nanodegree--nd009">https://www.udacity.com/course/machine-learning-engineer-nanodegree--nd009</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>This article, as well as a guide for beginners in Data Science also serves as a personal goal for my career. Studying theses materials and continue with my specializations.</p>

<p>What do you think of this guide? Was it helpful for you? Comment below and see you soon!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
